You're alive!
生きていたのね イチカ
I knew it!
私 信じてたわ
大丈夫なの
Are you okay? You're not hurt, are you?
どこにも 怪我はない
別に怪我はしてないけど
I'm not hurt.
Why are you here? Did you come to see me?
それより どうしたの
私に会いに来てくれた
I came looking for you!
探してたのよ
Do you know how worried we were after you went missing?
あなたが行方不明になって
私達がどれだけ心配したか
Missing?
行方不明ってどうして
You activated the distress signal, didn't you?
あなたが緊急救難信号を発信したんでしょう
Well, that was... kind of an accident.
あれは 事故っていうか
なら どうして 救助に向かった無人ボットの反応がロストしたの
Then why was the signal from the rescue pod lost?
Well, one thing led to another, and...
そ それは
いろいろあって
I...
俺が
Uh, that was my fault.
あいや 僕がやったんです
Well... I mean, she was in danger, so I...
先輩 イチカさんが危険だと思って その
君は
Who are you?
Let me introduce you.
お姉ちゃんに紹介するね
This is Kirishima Kaito. He's my, uh, boyfriend.
霧島海人君 私の その
彼氏さんっていうか
Nice to meet you.
ど どうも はじめまして
What were you thinking, Ichika?!
何考えてんだよ イチカ
Not only are you interacting with the locals, one of them is your boyfriend?!
原生住民と接触するどころか
恋人作るってどういうこと
That hurts!
あなた 連盟法分かってる ね 分かってる
You know Federation law, don't you?
Um...
Aren't you interacting with him too?
お姉さんだって海人君と接触してる
I came to save your life! This is an emergency!
私は助けに来たの
非常事態なの
Stop it! That hurts!
私も非常事態
Do you realize how worried our family's been?!
私達家族がどれだけ心配したと思ってるの
You don't get what's going on, do you?!
あなた今の状況 何も分かってないでしょう
That really hurts!
痛いぃぃぃ
Castle Park
Lemon, you're late.
檸檬先輩 遅いっすよ
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，请登录www.kamigami.org
日听：秋水无痕 翻译：yaya 校对：小草爱吃梨 Syura 时间轴：小青
I was thinking too much about how the story should continue.
今後のストーリーを考えすぎてて
Where are Ichika and Kirishima?
イチカと霧島君は
まだ来てないっす
Not here yet.
I wonder if they got the time wrong.
集合時間 間違えてるのかな
Tanigawa, sorry to ask, but could you go take a look?
谷川さん 悪いけど
見に行ってもらえる
Allow me to introduce myself.
改めてご挨拶させてもらうわね
I'm Ichika's older sister, Takatsuki Emika.
イチカの姉の貴月絵美夏です
I'm Kirishima Kaito.
霧島海人です
Kirishima, huh? I'm grateful you took care of Ichika after she crash-landed.
霧島海人君ね
事故にあったイチカを保護してくれて ありがとう
I thank you on behalf of our family.
家族を代表して
お礼申し上げます
Oh, it was nothing.
あ いいえ
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
本当にご迷惑をおかけしました
I'll be taking Ichika back myself.
イチカは 私が連れて帰りますので
Sis!
お姉ちゃん
A distress call was received from a remote planet,
辺境惑星からの救難信号
and contact was lost with the rescue pod that was sent to save you.
救出に向かった無人ボットの通信途絶
イチカ 今のあなたは遭難者どころか
You're not just shipwrecked, Ichika. You're considered missing!
行方不明者扱いになってるの
Do you know how worried we were when we heard that?
それを知った私達が
どれだけ心配したか分かる
All our relatives are talking about it.
親戚中大騒ぎになってるのよ
So I took a paid vacation, rented the latest ship,
だから 私が有給とって
最新鋭の船をレンタルして
and came out here to do my best to find you.
必死になってあなたを探しにきたの
それが何
And what do I find?
While I was worried sick, you're living here without a care in the world, and you even have a boyfriend!
これだけ心配かけたくせに
能天気に暮らしてるどころか
彼氏まで作って
I'm sorry!
ご ごめんなさい
I didn't think people would make such a big deal about it...
そんなに大事になってるとは 思わなくて
あ あの お姉さん
Um, dear Sis...
I think I might like the sound of that.
悪くない響きね
Having a younger guy call me that once in a while wouldn't be so bad.
年下の男の子から そう言われるの
なかなか新鮮
There shouldn't be any more problems now that you know she's safe, right?
その イチカさんの無事が分かったんですから
もう 問題ないですよね
That's true!
ああ 確かに
They've already formed a search party.
捜索すでに始まっているの
But if you report back that I'm safe...
でも 私が無事だって報告すれば
You went missing on a development level F planet where interaction with the locals is strictly forbidden.
開発レベルＦ
原生住民との接触が許されない
辺境惑星での行方不明者
I'm sure the Federation would want to verify the situation as quickly as possible.
連盟とすれば
一刻も早く状況を確認したいはずよ
If they found you and found out what you've been doing, you'd be arrested on the spot.
もしあなたを見つけ 今していることを知ったら
即座に逮捕拘束
You would be prosecuted in accordance with Federation law.
連盟法によって裁かれることになるわ
But...
そんな
Is there nothing you can do?
どうにかならないんですか
That's why I'm here.
だから 私が来たの
Ichika, come home with me before things gets out of hand.
イチカ 事が大きくなる前に
私と一緒に帰るのよ
But...
そんな
やだ
I don't want to...
I can't leave Kaito!
海人君と離れない
I just can't!
絶対に離れない
If you stay here, you'll only cause problems for Kirishima and the rest of the planet.
あんたが留まれば
霧島君やこの星にも迷惑を掛けることになるわ
I haven't done anything wrong.
私 何も悪いことなんてしてない
That's not the problem here.
そういう問題じゃないの
Why can't you understand?!
どうして 分かってくれないの
Please, calm down...
先輩 落ち着いて
Let's listen to your sister and think of a way—
お姉さんの話をちゃんと聞いて
どうすればいいかを…
There's only one choice.
どうすることもできないわ
イチカ あなたなら 分かるでしょう
Ichika, you must already know, right?
Rinon!
りのん
Ichika!
先輩
Ichika...
ごめんなさい 霧島君
Kirishima, I'm sorry...
みっともないところを見せてしまって
that you had to see this.
It's okay.
いいえ
貴月 先輩
Takatsuki! Hey...
谷 川さん
Tani...
gawa?
何してるんですか
What are you doing? We were supposed to start filming ages ago.
撮影時間 とっくに 過ぎちゃってます よ
なんで 靴履いてないんですか
Why aren't you wearing any shoes?
Takatsuki?
先輩
あ あの
Um...
Does she...
先 あ いえ
Does she really have to go home?
イチカさんは
どうしても 帰らなくちゃいけないんですか
She does.
いけないわ
一度 戻って またここに来るとか
Could she go home and then come back here again?
Given the situation, I imagine that would be difficult.
こんな状況だし それは難しいでしょうね
だったら
Then...
Then could you take me into space with you?!
だったら 俺を 一緒に 宇宙に連れて行ってもらえませんか
I'll do anything!
俺 何でもしますから
あんながさつで意固地な子で
My sister's not very elegant, and she's stubborn. Are you sure about that?
本当にいいの
Yes!
はい
少し 場所を変えましょうか
How about a change of scenery?
Y-You're going back?
か 帰るって
They're already looking for me.
私の捜索はもう始まってて
とても逃げ切れるような相手じゃないの
I couldn't get away from them if I tried,
and I don't think they'd listen to what I had to say either.
話し合いにも応じないと思う
Is there nothing you can do?
どうにもならないんですか
Things would only get worse if I tried to stay.
無理に残ろうとしたら
きっと大変なことに
だから 私は
So I have to...
So you're just gonna leave?
行っちゃうんですか
You're gonna leave Kaito behind and go back into space?
海人君を残して 宇宙に行っちゃうんだ
But I can't do anything about it...
でも もう私にはどうすることも
So you're going to give up on being with the guy you like?!
好きな人と一緒にいること 諦めるんですね
So you went out with him knowing that you'd just give up because your feelings for him weren't that strong?
そんな簡単に諦めるような気持ちで
その程度の気持ちで海人君と付き合ってたんですか
Do you... Do you have any idea what that's like for me?
私が 私がどんな気持ちで
Tanigawa...
谷川さん
勝手にすれば
Just do whatever you want! Just give up already and go back to space or whatever!
あきらめて 好きな人残して
宇宙でもなんでも行っちゃえ
この星 いいところね
This is a nice planet.
こんなに自然が残ってる
There are trees and wildlife everywhere.
It's nothing like our planet, but it still feels like I've been here before.
私の星とは全然違うのに
なんだか 懐かしいわ
Ichika said the same thing.
イチカさんも 同じこと 言ってました
She said there's an image of a place in her memories, and it's somewhere on this planet.
自分の頭の中にある イメージの場所が
この星にあるって
That's why she came to this planet.
だから この星に来たんだって
That image is inside me too.
そのイメージね 私の中にもあるの
恐らく だけど
It's probably...
something our ancestors encoded into themselves as genetic data.
イチカや私の先祖が
そのイメージを遺伝子データに組み込んだのね
And we've inherited it.
私達は それを受け継いでいるのよ
Why would they do that?
どうして そんなことを
Maybe that's where they buried a bunch of treasure or something?
さあ
ご先祖のお宝でも埋まっているのかしらね
私はそんなの気にしないけど
I don't really care that much about it, but Ichika seems to.
イチカはずっとそのイメージを引きずっていたのかもしれない
When I came for Ichika, I scanned the whole planet,
イチカを探すときに
この星全体をスキャンしてみたけど
イメージと合致する場所は見つからなかったんだけどね
but I couldn't find anything that matched the memory I have.
I...
あの
I know you said you want to go into space with us,
一緒に宇宙に行きたいって話したけど
but I can't take someone from a development level F planet into space.
開発レベルＦの住人を宇宙に連れて行くことはできないわ
This planet would first have to develop the technology for interstellar travel,
この星の人々が恒星間航行できるほどの技術を得て
make contact with us, and join the Galactic Federation
私達と接触し 銀河連盟に加わって
before that could happen.
そうなって 初めて 霧島君の望みは叶う
For that to happen, this planet would probably require hundreds of Earth years of development.
そうなるまで
この星の標準時間で
何百年もの時間が必要でしょうけど
Is there... Is there really no other way?
何が 何が別の方法が
Short of changing Federation law, no.
連盟法が改正でもされない限りは
無理ね
ありがとう 霧島君
Thank you, Kirishima.
You care about Ichika so much...
イチカのことをそんなに思ってくれて
でも イチカは連れて帰るわ
but...
I have to bring her home.
それが あの子のためなの
It's for her own good.
I never thought she'd get a boyfriend.
あの子に 彼氏がいたってなんて
I only came here to get her. I didn't think all this would happen.
せっかく迎えに来たのに
なんだか損な役回り
貴月イチカさんの お姉さんですね
You are Takatsuki Ichika's sister, correct?
誰
Who's there?!
柑菜 戻ってこないね
Kanna hasn't come back yet.
Lemon's gone too.
檸檬先輩もどっか行っちゃうし
ったく 海たちも何やってんだか
And what are Kai and Ichika doing?
I hope he's not fooling around while we're supposed to be filming.
撮影忘れていちゃついてんじゃねえだろうな
I count myself lucky, though.
私は ちょっとラッキーだな
そうか
Really?
Really.
そうですよ
何がそうなの
Really what?
柑菜
Kanna!
か 海たちは
Where're Kai and Ichika?
知らない
Dunno.
What's wrong, Kanna?
どうしたの 柑菜
Takatsuki said she's going back to space. Someone's come to take her back.
貴月先輩が宇宙に行くんだって
迎えが来るんだって
What?!
Says it's complicated. She's got no choice.
事情があるんだって
どうしようもないんだって
We're not making the movie anymore, so there's no reason to wait around. Let's go home!
だから 映画作りもお終い
ここにいても無駄だから 帰りましょう
Wait... Wait, Kanna.
ちょ ちょっと待って 柑菜
What?
何
Does Takatsuki really want to go back to space?
貴月先輩はホントに宇宙へ行きたいって思ってるの
How would I know...
そんなの
What about Kai?!
海はどうなるんだよ
Are you okay with this?
いいのかよ
Takatsuki will vanish and leave Kai behind.
海を残して 先輩が行っちまって
Is that what you want? Are you sure?
このままでいいのか
柑菜はそれで本当にいいのかよ
Of...
そんなの
Of course not!
いいわけないでしょう
I was talking to your sister until just a little while ago.
さっきまで お姉さんと話してました
宇宙に連れててって言ったら
I asked her to let me come with you, but she said I couldn't.
断られましたけど
俺 諦めてませんから
I haven't given up on finding a way to stay with you.
先輩と一緒にいられる方法
Tanigawa got mad at me.
私ね 谷川さんに怒られちゃった
え どうして
Why?
Ichika? Don't tell me!
先輩 まさか
Rinon, teleport me.
りのん 私をジャンプさせて
Ichika!
せ 先輩
Not so fast.
だーめ
先輩 諦めるのは早くねえっすか
Aren't you giving up a little too easily?
Tetsuro...
哲郎
Kitahara...
北原さんも
Kanna told us what happened, so we came here.
事情聞きました
だから来ました
ほっとけねえ よな
We couldn't just let you go like that.
We won't allow it. I mean, if you left, we wouldn't be able to finish the movie.
こ 困るんですよね
貴月先輩がいなくなると 映画取れなくなるし
Tanigawa...
谷川さん
I want you to stay here, Takatsuki!
私 貴月先輩にここにいてほしいです
Me too!
俺も
But...
で でも
You have Kirishima here!
ここには 霧島君がいるんですよ
But...
でも
Be honest!
本音を言ってよ
What is it that you really want?
先輩は本当はどうしたいんですか
I don't want to go.
行きたくない
I don't want to go home.
帰りたくない
I don't want to leave him.
離れたくない
I love Kaito...
海人君が 好きなの
俺も好きです
I love you too!
一緒にいたい
I want to stay with you!
I don't care if the entire galaxy is against us!
宇宙ぐらい敵にまわしたってどうってことない
Kaito...
海人君
だったらそうしろ
Then that's what you should do!
Thank you.
ありがとう
So what now? Are you going to run?
で どうする
逃げるか
Are you going to hide somewhere?
どこかに隠れるとか
Well...
そ それは
Seems like you have a problem on your hands.
困っているようね
檸檬
Lemon?
I have some good news for you.
そんなあなた達に朗報があるな
Episode Eleven
Please don't go...
She can stay here on Earth?
先輩が地球に残れる
Yes. Though I wouldn't say our chances are good.
ええ 可能性は限りなく低いけれど
It's still something, though.
でもゼロではないわ
What should I do?
何をすればいいの
Ichika, you said you were looking for a place from your memory, right?
イチカ あなたは頭の中にあるイメージの場所っていうのを探してたのよね
Yeah...
Then that means there's a possibility that aliens have come to Earth before, correct?
だとすると
この地球には 以前にも宇宙人が来たことがあると考えられないかしら
But they're just something I saw in my head...
で でも そこはあくまで 私のイメージで
Archives
先輩のお姉さんが言ってた
Her sister said she knew what Ichika was thinking of,
自分の中にも先輩と同じイメージの風景があるって
but that there is no such place on Earth.
でも 地球にそれらしい場所はないって
Putting an image into someone's mind is incredibly complex.
記憶にイメージを残すなんて
手のこんだことをしたのよ
They may have used some method to make it impossible to find with their technology.
その場所には
イチカたちの技術では見つけられない装置が施されているかもしれない
Nagano Province
Detailed maps
なら 調べようが
Nagano Province
Detailed maps
Then how do we find it?
Nagano Province
Detailed maps
We can try comparing the data you've gathered with maps of Earth.
イチカが調べたデータを地球の地図で比較してみるのよ
Of course! If there's a place missing from their records but on the maps, we've got it!
そうか もし データいない場所が地図に載っていたら
そこが
Lemon, how did you figure that out?
檸檬 あなた どうやってそのことを
Someone gave me some advice.
助言してくれた人がいるの
それって
You mean...
You knew I was being so selfish, but you still...
お姉ちゃん
私 あんなにわがまま言ったのに
Thank your friend, Ichika.
お友達に感謝することね イチカ
There's not much time. Get to work.
時間がないわよ 急ぎなさい
If we find that place, and there are signs of contact with aliens,
その場所を見つけて
そこに地球人と異星人が接触していた痕跡があれば
Earth will be promoted from level F.
地球は開レベルＦの惑星ではなくなる
We have to find it before the search party arrives.
捜索隊が来る前に見つけることが出来れば
Takatsuki!
先輩 イメージの風景は日本に限定していいんですよね
You're certain we can restrict our search to Japan, right?
うん その中にあった植物の生息具合から
Yeah. Judging from the plants and surroundings in the image I have, we can limit our search to just Shinshu.
信州に限定していいと思う
絶対に探しだす
We'll definitely find it!
Yeah!
おう
Something's coming...
なんか来る
右から
From the right...
Go get some sleep, Kai.
海も少し寝ろよ
We don't know when they'll come for her.
けど いつ先輩の迎えが来るか
なら 眠気覚ましにいいこと教えてやるよ
Then I'll tell you something to help you stay awake.
What is it?
いいこと
I told Kanna I liked her the other day.
この前 柑菜に告った
ウソ お前 何それ
Huh? You... You what?!
I already knew her answer, though.
結果分かってたんだけどな
Is that why you told me about her?
お前 だから 谷川のことを俺に
I was thinking too much about myself.
俺はさ 俺のことばかり考えすぎてたんだ
I didn't want you to end up the same way.
だから お前にはそうなって欲しくねえ
Tetsuro...
哲郎
And when we were in Okinawa, Mio told me she liked me.
あとな 沖縄に行ったとき
美桜に告られた
マジで
Seriously?
Seriously.
マジで
After I got into high school, I hadn't really been doing anything,
なんかさ 高校入って何もしてなくて
so I thought I'd at least do something for the summer, and I guess I got my wish.
なんかしたいと思ってたら
いろんなこと起こっちゃったな
Yeah, especially after Ichika came.
先輩が来てからは特にな
This summer's been amazing.
この夏はすげえよ
Yeah.
After all, we're talking about spaaace!
なんだって 宇宙だしな
It's out of my hands now,
これぐらいしかできないけど
見つかるといいわね イチカ
but I hope you find it, Ichika.
The place you're looking for...
あなたの場所が
and your future.
未来が
When did I fall asleep?
俺 いつの間に
You can sleep a little longer.
もう少し寝てていいわよ
私達も起きたから
We're already up.
You wanna sleep on my lap?
なんなら 私の膝で寝る
え あ いや
I'm okay...
何ラブラブしてんですか
Why are you guys acting so lovey-dovey?
I wasn't trying to.
そういうわけじゃ
Yeah, me neither.
ええ 別に
What happened?!
何だ
I found it! This place hasn't been checked!
み 見つけた
チェックされてない場所
Ichika!
先輩
Ichika, can you hear me?
イチカ 聞こえてる
Sis!
お姉ちゃん
The search party is approaching the planet.
捜索隊が 惑星の近くに
You need to hurry...
早く  そこから
お姉ちゃん
Sis!
Ichika!
先輩
りのん 急いでさっきのポイントへ私達をジャンプさせて
Rinon, hurry and teleport us there!
Rinon, what's wrong?
りのん
どうしたの
Oh no, there's a linkage anti-field deployed over the entire planet?
そんな リンケージのアンチフィールドが
惑星レベルで張り巡らされてる
You can't teleport?
伝送ができない
What now? Even by train it's three hours away!
どうする 電車で行くとしても三時間はかかるぜ
They're nearby!
追手が来てるんでしょう
We have to hurry!
早くしなきゃ
What the hell?
なんだ こりゃ
There's no driver?
無人
It's me.
私よ
Lemon?!
檸檬先輩
こんなことがあろうかと 車を用意しておいてよかったわ
I thought this might happen, so I'm glad I prepared this car.
Do you have a license?
先輩 免許持ってたんっすか
ええ 一通り
Yes, most of them.
Most of them?
迎えってどんな人が来るの
Who's going to be coming after you?
I wonder what else she has...
Probably another rescue pod like before.
多分 この前と同じ救助ボットだと思うけど
Ichika, they're going to come after you by scanning for your biological data, right?
イチカ
相手はあなたの生体データをスキャンして追ってくるのよね
Yeah, but how do you know that?
ええ でも どうして
これを羽織って
Put this on.
It'll reduce the biological responses you're giving off.
あなたが放つ生体反応を軽減してくれるわ
I also have these devices that'll transmit biological data identical to Ichika's when activated.
それから
この装置
スイッチを入れると イチカの生体データと同等のものを発信するわ
檸檬
Lemon, did you get these from...
もしかして これも
That's right. I had your sister's help.
そう あなたのお姉さんに協力してもらったの
姉ちゃん
Thank you, Sis...
Okay, let's keep heading toward—
よしゃ このまま目的地まで
It'll rip apart the car!
ぎ ギシギシ言ってる
No way!
ま まさか
It's coming after us!
追手だ
Getting closer!
また来る
Ishigaki!
石垣君
Got it.
了解
私も
Me too!
I'm going too!
私も行く
Mio!
美桜
Let me go with you!
一緒に行かせて
哲郎
Tetsuro!
You better make it there, Kai!
必ず 辿りつけよ 海
Good luck!
頑張って
美桜 スイッチ
Mio, turn it on!
Okay!
はい
ほら ほら よってこい よってこい
Catch us if you can!
Gotcha!
ビンゴ
Tetsuro!
哲郎
Mio!
美桜
What?
何
今度さ 映画行かない
Wanna go see a movie sometime?
Not with Kanna or Kai! Just us!
柑菜と海抜きで 二人で
うん 行く
Yeah, let's go!
Lemon, take Route 75!
檸檬先輩
７５線に入ってください
We're about...
残り あと １０キロ強
ten kilometers away.
Behind us!
後ろ
There's more of them!
まだいる
私が降ります
I'll go.
谷川さん
Tanigawa!
先輩のためにやるんじゃないんです
I'm not doing this for you.
大好きな人のためにやるんです
I'm doing it for the one I love!
私の大好きな人には
I want the one I love to keep smiling.
笑顔でいてほしいから
Tanigawa!
谷川
I'm gonna make you regret this three years from now!
三年後 死ぬほど後悔させてやるんだから
Be happy, you jerk!
幸せになれ ばーか
We lost them.
追手 いないみたいです
Take this, Kirishima.
霧島君
これを
俺のカメラ
My camera?
What are we gonna do?
何をするの
決まってるでしょう
Isn't it obvious? We're gonna continue filming.
撮影をするのよ
The heroine evades her pursuers' attacks and heads toward her final destination.
ヒロインは敵の攻撃をかいくぐり 目的地を目指す
I can't think of a better climax.
素敵なクライマックスが撮れそうね
We'll leave the epilogue to God.
そして エピローグは神任せ
That's the best part of making a movie.
これも また 映画作りの醍醐味よ
I'm ready!
準備オッケーです
And... action!
よい スタート
I looked for the reason why I fell in love
and tried solemn words
Persistent, are we?
こしゃくね
Once I realized my feelings,
What's up with this car?!
な 何なんです この車
the threads had gotten hopelessly tangled up
If I'd been able to say it
without hesitation
you wouldn't have to cry now
Episode Twelve
Waiting there, in the summer.
We'll never forget...
...the extraordinary summer we spent together.
No matter how much time may pass, we'll be...
Episode Twelve
Waiting there, in the summer.
...waiting there, in the summer.
僕達はきっと忘れない
皆と過ごした 特別な夏を
どんなに時が流れても
僕達は あの夏で待ってる